

Matt Radbourne

63A Caledonian Road London N1 9BT Phone: +44 7956 449911
Email: m@radbourne.me
Web: radbourne.me

I am a user experience designer with four years experience at several of London's leading UX companies. I have a formal education in user-centred design, receiving first-class honours. I lead UX, design and development teams in large programmes of work and have fun doing it.

Skills

Soft skills

- Perform well on high pressure projects, managing teams and budgets where necessary.
- Understand clients' business objectives and opportunities in order to propose effective methodologies and solutions.
- Deliver presentations and research debriefs clearly and confidently whilst adhering to a strict schedule.
- Observe but do not limit myself to existing interaction design conventions and trends.
- Constantly build on my authoritative voice in the industry to become a widely recognised expert in the field.
- Propose initiatives and help optimise and standardise processes in the organisation.

User research

- Conduct qualitative and quantitative user research such as depth interviews, prototype testing, diary studies, card sorts and focus groups.
- Adapt research for different types of participant, including stakeholders, SMEs, existing and prospective users.
- Combine user research and interaction design skills in an iterative workflow.

Web development

- Work with teams in Agile sprints to provide developers with effective feedback and instructions instead of time-consuming deliverables.
- Use technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP and MySQL to build high fidelity interactive prototypes.
- Strictly adhere to web standards and WCAG accessibility guidelines to build and deploy accessible websites.
- Capture, edit and output digital video and audio to broadcast and web standards.

Interaction design

- Design usable, efficient and persuasive interfaces that address different user needs and contexts.
- Employ special considerations to design for different input methods (e.g. touch), different types of device and cross-platform interfaces.
- Create high quality deliverables such as wireframes, diagrams and high fidelity graphic designs to communicate interaction design recommendations.
- Use primary research insight to create personas, scenarios, user journeys and specific design recommendations.
- Produce rapid interactive prototypes to support RITE testing and iterative workflows.

Information architecture

- Organise digital information to aid orientation, navigation and overall usability.
- Create effective data labelling, categorisation and relationships.
- Document sitemaps and process flow charts using Jesse James Garrett's Visual Vocabulary.

Visual design

- Utilise a strong understanding of visual design concepts such as grids, ratios and colour theory.
- Achieve consistent colour across print or web workflows through strict use of ICC profiles and manual colour-matching.
- Conduct productive critiques with other designers around design decisions and direction.

Software

After Effects, Axure, Balsamiq, Coda, Dreamweaver, Final Cut Studio, Fireworks, Flash, Illustrator, InDesign, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Project, Morae, NVivo, OmniGraffle, Optimal Workshop suite, Photoshop, Silverback, Sketch, Tobii Studio.

Competent on Mac OS X and Windows. Always keen to learn new and better tools.



Professional experience



Senior Designer at Foolproof

September 2014 - Present

I focus on interaction design and UX consultancy work. I lead teams in large design projects and am responsible for managing the Agile delivery of live code. I check and critique work as part of my quality assurance role. I also own initiatives such as the device lab and accessibility initiative.



UX Teaching Assistant at General Assembly

January 2015 - April 2015

During the UX design lectures given by the instructor, I was on-hand to answer questions and give examples to the students. The course was made up of several workshop sessions that I helped structure in order to demonstrate different UX processes and tools.



Interaction Designer at Flow Interactive

July 2013 - September 2014

I led interaction design projects and managed a team of contractors in RITE testing and delivering B2B software designs. I also led design concept prioritisation workshops with senior clients.



UX Consultant at Foolproof

September 2011 - July 2013

I led and supported on many usability testing and ethnography projects, including a five-country diary study on online gambling. I set up and conducted lab-based research around the country and overseas.



Design Intern at Float (Now Prosper)

June 2010 - July 2010

I produced and populated the company's HTML email newsletter templates and designed a Flash-based 3D Twitter visualisation for a Meetup event.



Designer at College of Estate Management

November 2005 - September 2011

I had a key role in the design and production of CEM's new e-learning offering. I also produced print and digital design work for the Marketing department.

Activities

- · Presenting and speaking about UX design to students and the UX community.
- Helping at industry events and workshops such as UXPA workshop sessions and BBC Freeformers student days.
- Taking part in public design events such as Design Jam London and Near Field Norwich.

Education

In my BA(Hons) Interactive Media Design at the University of East London, I focused on user experience and emotional design. I received First Class Honours for my third-year thesis and multimedia project in which I created collaborative educational games that are projected onto the floor and controlled with infrared light. I worked with pupils and teachers at a London primary school to produce and test the games. The project has been featured on LBC 97.3 FM, showcased for the Minister for Digital Britain and published in the East London Advertiser and Wharf newspapers.

Recent awards

- I won the 2011 UEL Interactive Media Award for Outstanding Level 3 Research.
- I won a prize for contribution to Foolproof's "authoritative voice" initiative by writing the blogs 'User control and responsive design' and 'Advantages of in-field international research.'

Reference

"Matt is great person to work with and I'm glad to know him. He is incredibly creative and enthusiastic about UX design. His talents stretch from interface development using the Adobe suite and HTML5 as well as user research and design tools and methodologies." Stuart Scott, Interaction Lab Manager at City University London